- [Instructor] So now we want to install the zustand library,
and you can install it by using either NPM or Yarn.
So we're going to use this, npm i zustand.
So let's go back to our application.
We're going to install this one.
So we cannot really paste from the clipboard
with code spaces.
So I'm going to do npm i and then zustand
to install the library.
And while this is running, we're going to check out our app.
You're going to see that this is a very basic example,
where you can increment, decrement, and also reset to 0.
And back in our resource code, so now this is installed.
I'm just going to make sure that this is up and running again.
We're going to look at the source code.
And you can see that now we are using the React API
in order to manage the state.
And the concern here is that the state remains attached
to the same components.
And this can become quickly an issue
if you need to scale the up,
or maintaining the state can be a very tedious
and challenging task.
In previous examples,
we have seen that the application state
should never remain attached to a single components
or remain at the top level of the application tree.
Hence, the need to centralize the state management
and to keep the structure flat.
So that's why we're going to use zustand in this example.
And to get started, we're going to first create a store.
So let's go back here.
We're going to look at the documentation.
And first you need to import the function create
from the library zustand,
and we're going to be able to create a store,
which will be a hook.
So let's copy from this example.
Let's go back to our source code and the project,
the starter project.
And inside here we're going to go ahead and create a store.
And I'm going to paste those lines.
And the way it works is that the store is like a big hook
that can include anything, objects to all the states,
primitive data, and also functions to carry over the states.
So we're going to invoke the create functions from the library,
which is already in the scope.
And I'm going to name this hook useCounter.
For the initial state, it's going to be count that we set at 0.
And we're going to have three features to implement,
which is increment, decrement, and reset.
So let's set this up.
It's going to be increment.
And for now, I'm just going to leave this as an empty function.
Then it's going to be decrement.
Finally, reset, to reset the counter at 0.
And so the create function takes a callback function
that would hold the store data
with global states and actions, just like we did right here.
And what we're going to do right away
is to export default this useCounter hook
because we're going to need to use it outside.
And the store callback exposes a set function
and also a get function.
So we're going to use set to update the state,
but also get to read the state.
So the first thing we want to do is to read from the state.
We're going to need to have access to the count.
And just to show that this is private,
I'm going to do get and then count.
And after that, we're going to use set
in order to update the states.
So that's going to be this syntax.
And actually what it does is that it returns in object
that's going to be wrapped here
in another parenthesis, like this.
And then we're going to update the counts.
And actually let's just save some lines of code.
And we're going to do get counts + 1 to increments.
We don't need this line right here.
I'm going to do the same for decrement,
but actually it's going to be - 1, and same for resets.
And here we're going to reset the value at 0.
And I think that works.
So creating the store was an easy step.
The syntax is very similar to the context API,
but the only difference is that it doesn't require
the app components to be wrapped in a context provider.
So the data flow is very simple.
And next we're going to see
how to bind the components to the states.